<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>entry &#8211; phpDay 2016</title>
	<atom:link href="/level/entry/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>The international PHP Conference</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 18:00:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Drinking Beer with a Raspberry Pi and PHP</title>
		<link>/talk/drinking-beer-with-a-raspberry-pi-and-php/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:46:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=talk&#038;p=548</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Always been interested in the Raspberry Pi but never known what you could do with it? Got a Raspberry Pi at home that you played with for 5 minutes before you got bored? This talk is for you. We will be making a journey into the world of programming with sensors and other electrical components. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span data-sheets-value="[null,2,&quot;Always been interested in the Raspberry Pi but never known what you could do with it? Got a Raspberry Pi at home that you played with for 5 minutes before you got bored? This talk is for you. We will be making a journey into the world of programming with sensors and other electrical components. The concepts introduced will not be specific to any programming language, but we will use PHP throughout to keep it simple. The demonstration will show how you could use a Raspberry Pi to spice up a home bar. By the end of this talk, you will have acquired the skills to get started on your own hobby electronics projects! Maybe these skills will one day be handy introducing friends and family to the adventures of programming.&quot;]" data-sheets-userformat="[null,null,9089,[null,0],null,null,null,null,null,null,0,4,0,null,null,null,8]">Always been interested in the Raspberry Pi but never known what you could do with it? Got a Raspberry Pi at home that you played with for 5 minutes before you got bored? This talk is for you. We will be making a journey into the world of programming with sensors and other electrical components. The concepts introduced will not be specific to any programming language, but we will use PHP throughout to keep it simple. The demonstration will show how you could use a Raspberry Pi to spice up a home bar. By the end of this talk, you will have acquired the skills to get started on your own hobby electronics projects! Maybe these skills will one day be handy introducing friends and family to the adventures of programming.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Keep your users up-to-date in realtime with WebSockets!</title>
		<link>/talk/keep-your-users-up-to-date-in-realtime-with-websockets/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=talk&#038;p=543</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Live document collaboration, playing cooperative and competetive games, updating sports scores, booking seats. Stateless and belated nature of HTTP requests is not a perfect match for these and other similar use cases. WebSockets offer immediate delivery of messages in two-way communication between the client and the server. Instead of periodic polling for new messages, they [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span data-sheets-value="[null,2,&quot;Live document collaboration, playing cooperative and competetive games, updating sports scores, booking seats. Stateless and belated nature of HTTP requests is not a perfect match for these and other similar use cases. WebSockets offer immediate delivery of messages in two-way communication between the client and the server. Instead of periodic polling for new messages, they are pushed to the receiver over TCP/IP connection. Implementing WebSockets is not limited to technologies like node.js but has also been possible in PHP for quite some time with impressive results. In this talk, I will introduce this technology and tell the audience how to successfully adopt it in their PHP applications while avoiding problems and pitfalls.&quot;]" data-sheets-userformat="[null,null,9089,[null,0],null,null,null,null,null,null,0,4,0,null,null,null,8]">Live document collaboration, playing cooperative and competetive games, updating sports scores, booking seats. Stateless and belated nature of HTTP requests is not a perfect match for these and other similar use cases. WebSockets offer immediate delivery of messages in two-way communication between the client and the server. Instead of periodic polling for new messages, they are pushed to the receiver over TCP/IP connection. Implementing WebSockets is not limited to technologies like node.js but has also been possible in PHP for quite some time with impressive results. In this talk, I will introduce this technology and tell the audience how to successfully adopt it in their PHP applications while avoiding problems and pitfalls.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Build middleware applications with Zend Framework 3</title>
		<link>/talk/build-middleware-applications-with-zend-framework-3/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=talk&#038;p=539</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Zend Framework 3 offers the possibility to write PHP application using a middleware approach. With the usage of the component zend-expressive, combined with the PSR-7 standard, we will show how to build performant, well structured and reusable web applications. We will show how to design and implement simple web applications, APIs and complex web architectures [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span data-sheets-value="[null,2,&quot;[Zend Framework 3](http://framework.zend.com)/ offers the possibility to write PHP application using a middleware approach. With the usage of the component [zend-expressive](https://github.com/zendframework/zend-expressive), combined with the [PSR-7](http://www.php-fig.org/psr/psr-7/) standard, we will show how to build performant, well structured and reusable web applications. We will show how to design and implement simple web applications, APIs and complex web architectures using dependency injection containers, routing systems and template adapters.&quot;]" data-sheets-userformat="[null,null,9089,[null,0],null,null,null,null,null,null,0,4,0,null,null,null,8]"><a href="http://framework.zend.com/">Zend Framework 3 </a>offers the possibility to write PHP application using a middleware approach. With the usage of the component <a href="https://github.com/zendframework/zend-expressive">zend-expressive</a>, combined with the <a href="http://www.php-fig.org/psr/psr-7/">PSR-7</a> standard, we will show how to build performant, well structured and reusable web applications. We will show how to design and implement simple web applications, APIs and complex web architectures using dependency injection containers, routing systems and template adapters.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Machine learning for PHP</title>
		<link>/talk/machine-learning-for-php/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=talk&#038;p=538</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Machine learning is teaching the computer how to learn by itself. It is far easier to be done, especially when you have small data set and a good level of expertise in your field. Classifying objects, predicting who will buy, where to park your car or which test will fail may be achieved with grassy [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span data-sheets-value="[null,2,&quot;Machine learning is teaching the computer how to learn by itself. It is far easier to be done, especially when you have small data set and a good level of expertise in your field. Classifying objects, predicting who will buy, where to park your car or which test will fail may be achieved with grassy algorithm like neural networks, genetic algorithms or ant herding. PHP is in good position to make use of such teachings, and take advantages of related technologies like R. By the end of the session, you'll know where you want to try it.&quot;]" data-sheets-userformat="[null,null,9089,[null,0],null,null,null,null,null,null,0,4,0,null,null,null,8]">Machine learning is teaching the computer how to learn by itself. It is far easier to be done, especially when you have small data set and a good level of expertise in your field. Classifying objects, predicting who will buy, where to park your car or which test will fail may be achieved with grassy algorithm like neural networks, genetic algorithms or ant herding. PHP is in good position to make use of such teachings, and take advantages of related technologies like R. By the end of the session, you&#8217;ll know where you want to try it.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Your API is a UI</title>
		<link>/talk/your-api-is-a-ui/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 00:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=talk&#038;p=535</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Whether you&#8217;re creating a complex web application or a simple library, everything you create has a user. Why, then, do we concentrate on our users when developing a user interface, but so often forget them when developing APIs? In this talk, Christopher presents a whirlwind overview of a variety of different User Experience considerations when [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span data-sheets-value="[null,2,&quot;Whether you're creating a complex web application or a simple library, everything you create has a user. Why, then, do we concentrate on our users when developing a user interface, but so often forget them when developing APIs? In this talk, Christopher presents a whirlwind overview of a variety of different User Experience considerations when designing your APIs.&quot;]" data-sheets-userformat="[null,null,9089,[null,0],null,null,null,null,null,null,0,4,0,null,null,null,8]">Whether you&#8217;re creating a complex web application or a simple library, everything you create has a user. Why, then, do we concentrate on our users when developing a user interface, but so often forget them when developing APIs? In this talk, Christopher presents a whirlwind overview of a variety of different User Experience considerations when designing your APIs.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.w3-edge.com/products/

Page Caching using apc

 Served from: 2016.phpday.it @ 2017-02-13 19:04:57 by W3 Total Cache -->